Human speech contains more than 2,000 different sounds, from the common “m” and “a” to the rare clicks of some southern African languages.
人类言语中包含2000多种不同的语音，从常见的“m”和“a”，到非洲南部一些语言中罕见的咂音。
But why are certain sounds more common than others?
但为什么某些语音比其他语音更常见呢？
A ground-breaking, five-year study shows that diet-related changes in human bite led to new speech sounds that are now found in half the world’s languages.
一项开创性的、为期五年的研究表明，与饮食相关的人类咬合变化带来了新的语音，如今世界上一半的语言中都有这些语音。
More than 30 years ago, the scholar Charles Hockett noted that speech sounds called labiodentals, such as “f” and “v”, were more common in the languages of societies that ate softer foods.
30多年前，学者查尔斯·霍凯特就注意到，在吃较软食物的社会里，语言中“f”“v”这类被称为唇齿音的语音更为常见。
Now a team of researchers led by Damián Blasi at the University of Zurich, Switzerland, has found how and why this trend arose.
如今，由瑞士苏黎世大学达米安·布拉西领导的一个研究团队，已经查明了这一趋势是如何出现、又为何出现的。
They discovered that the upper and lower front teeth of ancient human adults were aligned, making it hard to produce labiodentals, which are formed by touching the lower lip to the upper teeth.
他们发现，远古成年人的上下门牙是对齐的，因此很难发出唇齿音，而唇齿音要靠下唇接触上齿才能发出。
Later, our jaws changed to an overbite structure, making it easier to produce such sounds.
后来，我们人类的颌部变成了覆咬合结构，这类音发起来就更容易了。
The team showed that this change in bite was connected with the development of agriculture in the Neolithic period.
研究团队证明，咬合的这一变化与新石器时代农业的发展有关。
Food became easier to chew at this point.
这时，食物变得更容易咀嚼了。
The jawbone didn’t have to do as much work and so didn’t grow to be so large.
颌骨不必再那么费力，因此也就没有长得那么大。
Analyses of a language database also confirmed that there was a global change in the sound of world languages after the Neolithic age, with the use of “f” and “v” increasing remarkably during the last few thousand years.
对一个语言数据库的分析也证实，新石器时代之后，世界语言的语音发生了全球性的变化：在过去几千年里，“f”和“v”的使用显著增多。
These sounds are still not found in the languages of many hunter-gatherer people today.
如今，在许多狩猎采集民族的语言中，仍然没有这些音。
This research overturns the popular view that all human speech sounds were present when human beings evolved around 300,000 years ago.
这项研究推翻了一种流行的观点：人类大约在30万年前进化形成时，所有语音就已经存在了。
“The set of speech sounds we use has not necessarily remained stable since the appearance of human beings, but rather the huge variety of speech sounds that we find today is the product of a complex interplay of things like biological change and cultural evolution,” said Steven Moran, a member of the research team.
“自人类出现以来，我们所使用的这套语音并不一定一直保持稳定；相反，今天我们看到的种类繁多的语音，是生物变化和文化演化等因素复杂交互作用的产物。”研究团队成员史蒂文·莫兰说。